# Marouane Khabbaz

Marwane.khab@gmail.com (347) 483-0376 New York, NY

# **Full Stack Developer**

<u>GitHub</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> Portfolio

### **Summary**

I am a Full Stack Developer proficient in HTML, CSS, React Js and Node.js. I also have three years of experience in biology, which helps me learn how to pay attention to details and improve my analytical thinking skills. I'm eligible to work in the United States without restrictions. Seeking a Full Stack Web Developer position utilizing React and Express.

#### **Skills**

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, React, React Hooks, Redux, Bootstrap, Jquery.

Back End: Node.js, Postgres, Knex Js, Express Js.

Additional Skills: Debugging, Test Driven Development, Mocha, Chai, Github, Git, Vercel, Heroku, NPM.

# **Recent Projects**

### Restaurant Reservation App | Project Link

- This app is a reservation system for fine dining restaurants. The software is used by restaurant personnel when a customer calls to request a reservation.
- Built using JavaScript, React, Express, Node, PostgreSQL, KnexJS, Cors, HTML, CSS, and BootStrap.
- Create a Rest API using Express and user interface using React.

#### Flashcard-o-Matic | Repo: Project Link

- Developed a flashcard application, this app is designed to help students study online.
- Built using JavaScript, React, HTML, and Bootstrap.
- Manage States using React Hooks like useState, useEffect.

#### backend-WeLoveMovies | Repo: Project Link

- Setting up a database and Building up a REST API with specific routes so that users can list, read, create, update or delete data about movies, theaters, and reviews.
- Built using Node js, knex Js, Express Js, Postgres, CORS package, deployed to Heroku.

## **Experience**

### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER TRAINEE**

Remote

### **THINKFUL**

JAN 2021 - JUL 2021

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards, with a focus on HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
   Node, React, Express, PostgreSQL, algorithm, and data structure.
- Collaborated with a senior web developer mentor for several hours a week.

SELF EMPLOYED Jersey City, NJ

City Cafe & Bakery AUG 2018 – JUN 2020

• Maintained high standards of quality control, cleanliness, and safety.

- Created marketing strategies to track existing and new customers.
- Controlled inventory of supply on a weekly basis to minimize costs.
- Ensured the integrity of restaurant operations through excellence in customer relations.

#### VETERINARY LABORATORY TECHNICIAN

New Hyde Park, NY

#### **Antech Diagnostics**

FEB 2017 - AUG 2018

- Performed lab analyses to provide data for diagnosis, treatment, and prevention of disease.
- Provided test results for diagnosis and treatment by operating hematology, urinalysis.

Followed lab protocols, sanitation standards, and testing procedures.

# QUALITY CONTROL TECHNICIAN

#### COPAG

Taroudant, Morocco JUL 2015 – OCT 2016

- Performed inspections across all stages of production.
- Ensured compliance to laws and quality norms, as well as company standards and specifications.
- Identified areas for quality control improvement and implement new methods accordingly.
- Communicated quality or compliance concerns with urgency.

# **Education**

# BACHELOR'S, BIOTECHNOLOGY

### University Sidi Mohammed Ben Abdallah | Fez, Morocco

SEP 2012 - JUN 2015

• Coursework: Physics, Mathematics, Chemistry, Biochemistry, Microbiology, Intro to programming.